A Guide to the Papers of the University History Officer, 1956-1979
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the University History Officer 1956-1979
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-3/5/1.791, RG-3/5/1.901
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection was an archival transfer from the University History Officer at an unknown date.
Scope and Content
The papers of the University History Officer, Charles E. Moran, contain general correspondence as well as topical files concerning the reprinting of Anna Barringer's memoirs; Virginius Dabney's history of the University of Virginia; Founder's Day; the inauguration of Frank L. Hereford; the Indian Massacre of 1622; a portrait of James Rogers McConnell; the Shannon Garden; Southampton County, Va.; University of Virginia history including a 1971 article on Jesse Beams, a copy of Eleanor Lile Tucker's memoirs, 1968, a copy of B. F. D. Runk's speech My friends, and a poem by Ray Bice honoring Senator Edward Stone; and the Virginia History and Museums Federation.
General correspondence includes information on Mrs. Lindsay Hay's copy of her father's Honor Men and the University of Virginia's housing Library of Congress documents during World War II.
Contents List
- General Correspondence, 1969-1976
- General Correspondence, 1977-1979, n.d.
- Barringer, Anna Maria: Pleasant it is to Remember these things, [1969-1974]
- Budget, 1976-1978
- Facilities, 1975-1979
- Founders Day, 1976
- Inaugural Committee, Frank Loucks Hereford, 1974-1975
- Indian Massacre of 1622, 1976
- McConnell, James Rogers: Portrait, 1977
- Printed Material re: University History, n. d.
- Shannon Garden, 1978
- Southampton County, Va., n. d.
- Virginius Dabney: Mr. Jefferson's University, [1961-1979]
- Virginia History and Museums Federation, [1979], 2 folders.